Welcome back. And today, we are going to
cover Kafka Streams architecture. So, in
the previous video, we have already seen
what's the need of the Kafka Streams.
Okay? So, today, let's go one level deep
and let's cover the architecture before
we do its uh understand how to create a
stream and all.
The very first
prerequisite is that we understand
the consumer setup part because
the Kafka Streams reuse much of the
Kafka consumer architecture itself. So,
if you're already cleared with this
Kafka consumer setup, and in the same,
I've also shared the Kafka consumer flow
also.
The Kafka Streams uses
the same architecture also.
Okay?
So,
that is the first, and the second
prerequisite is
Kafka Streams introduction. Like, why
exactly you need
Kafka Streams.
Okay? So, once this is clear,
let's start with Kafka Streams
architecture part.
So, first thing's first, if anyone asks
what is a stream, I would say that in
simple term,
a stream has no start, no end, and
events keep arriving.
So, like order one, order two, order
three, order four, it's never end. So,
that's what we call it as an a stream.
A stream processing means
processing events as they arrive
continuously in real time.
As when event come,
we are processing it, not like a batch.
Like, we run at 3:00 p.m. and then we
pick all the
events and then
processing it. No.
In real time, as the events arrive,
it will start processing it.
So, Kafka Streams is a client library
for building the stream processing
application.
So, one thing very specific is that the
Kafka stream is not like a cluster or
infrastructure, right? It's just a JAR
file. That's all.
Once we add this JAR in our application,
all this framework we will get
automatically.
Okay? So, it's simply a JAR file and we
have to add it in our application.
Okay. Now we know
what is a stream,
the very important part. You can say
that it's an heart of the stream, the
topology.
Now, let me stop it here and I will tell
you once the context here. Like
don't skip this part. Like if you are
trying to understand the architecture,
don't skip this part because
after that like even if you are
proceeding with the syntax, like how to
create a stream and different processors
in the streams, without this it will not
get clear and it is not very simple.
Okay? So, I'll try to go little slow
because from here itself now you can see
that the real architecture of Kafka
streams will start.
So, it's a logical flow of how data
moves and get proceed from source topic
to sink sink topics.
This flow is like a DAG, directed
acyclic graph.
Data flow in one direction, no loops, no
cycle.
Okay? So, what does it mean? Topology.
Topology means you can say that an
assembly line in a factory. So, you have
a factory.
So, it's like a first raw material.
Then after that different steps like you
cut it, you paint it,
you package it.
Then after that you will ultimately ship
it. So, you have a source.
You have a sink.
Okay? And then you have processors, like
different different steps.
So, you always So, it's a DAG, directed
acyclic graph. Means you always you have
a start point, you have an end point,
and from a start when you always move
forward. There is no loop or cycle.
Okay? You always move forward
and ultimately reach to a sink.
Okay? So, there can be Why it is a
graph? Because there can be multiple
source, there can be multiple sinks, or
there can be join also. I will show you.
But,
in simple, at this point of time, we
need to understand that topology is like
logical flow of how data moves and get
processed from source topics to sinks
topic.
So, here if you see,
we have a source. Let's say topic is
order-event. So, from here we have to
read it. So, it's like a raw material.
In a factory example, it's a raw
material.
Okay? And after that, we have our
processors, which can have, let's say,
multiple steps, like cut, paint,
package. Okay? And ultimately, we have a
sink, the output topic, like a shipping
of a finished material.
So, source is like an entry point, read
record from one or more Kafka topics, no
parent processor,
and source also like you can say that
here de- we deserialize bytes to
key-value pair, forward record to its
child processor.
Okay?
Now, here
is our actual business logic where
transformation happens.
Okay? You add filters, you add different
groups. We will see that. At this point
of time, you also don't have to worry
about like what all different processors
present and all, because we are
understanding architecture. We will see
processors later.
So, we have a business logic here, like
multiple steps we can do. Okay? And you
can say that we have When you have a
step one, a step two. So, whenever data
moves from a step one,
it do certain transformation and then
pass it to step two. It do certain
transformation, pass it to the step
three. Like this it data flows.
Okay? And ultimately it reach to the
sink, exit point, where record we write
record to the Kafka topic.
Okay?
So, this is let's say that for a
stateless processing.
Stateless processing and we have a
stateful processing. If you have
seen this Kafka stream introduction, we
have stateless processing and stateful
processing.
So, in a stateful processing,
we also uh store certain state.
Okay? While processing the record, so
this is our source, or raw material you
can say that.
So, we have this source topic.
From me, this source topic we read
even one by one and then we processes
it. Our business logic we can have
multiple step, step one, step two, step
three, step four.
Okay? So, it It is possible that in
certain step we have to
save the state. Let's say we are reading
total number of products. Okay?
So, product ID wise. So, let's say we we
have to store product ID one, then two,
then three. So, we have to store it
somewhere, right?
So, based on this for a stateful
processing, if you have certain
processor it has processors have you can
say that multiple steps, you can say
that multiple processing.
So, if certain processing need
to maintain the state,
it store it into the RocksDB.
We'll see that.
Okay?
So, this definition is clear?
Logical flow of data,
which moves and get processed from
source topics to sinks topic.
This is a DAG, data flow in one
direction, no loops and cycles.
So, we define it once during application
startup and after the Kafka stream
executed forever. So, topology is like
we define it into our configuration.
And when your application is start,
after that we can't change it. Okay? So,
after that this topology is used. We
will see that, but at this point of time
just understand that during application
startup
it reads our topology.
So, different examples of topology.
Let's say simple linear topology. You
have a source.
From source you get the data one by one.
Then this is our processors. Like
multiple steps you can say, multiple
processing.
Filter. Let's say greater than 100.
Okay? Don't worry about this for now.
Just assume that these are different
processings. Step step two.
So, filter then it maps. Ultimately
uh goes to the sink
and to the output topic. So, this is
linear.
Then we have branching topology.
The source.
From this source we will read even one
by one.
And then we have multiple processing.
You can say that branch what
we have. Filter greater than equals to
1,000, it goes to this branch. If filter
if your order is less than
1,000 rupees, let's say, it goes to a
different branch. Okay? So, its step
would be different. And ultimately it
will get sink. It is step would be
different. Ultimately it will get sink.
Multi-source join topology. You have
multiple source.
Then you will do a join.
And ultimately
you sink it. Okay? So, this is just an
example that I just wanted to mention
that topology is not like
a linear one like this simple.
It's not just like us linear. It can
have a branch. It can have a join.
That's why I said it's a DAG.
A graph. Directed acyclic graph. Like
it's but there would you will not find
any loop or circle.
Okay?
So, that's the same thing I mentioned
here. At this point of time, let's not
worry about how to create a stream. What
are the different processors like
filter, map? Don't worry about this one.
Okay? How to put that result into the
sink and all.
So, the over agenda here is to
understand the architecture. Okay? Next
part we will cover these topics.
Okay?
So, focus on the architecture part.
Don't worry about again that Okay,
filter, how to define that filter. Or
what all other processings are
available.
So, topology is clear, right?
Now, the next very important part is
task.
Read this once. It's a unit of
parallelism. You can say that the small
one task
Uh you can say that the smallest unit
which cannot be break further. I In a
simple way I can say that it say that
unit of parallelism. What does it mean?
Like
when we say parallelism, it's like we
are running multiple task task one task
two task three in parallel. Okay? Within
one task you can't run anything in
parallel. That's why it's a unit of
parallelism, the smallest task or the
smallest unit.
Okay? So, when we say parallelism in a
stream, it's mean multiple task are
running in parallel.
Okay?
Each task has complete topology. Means
every task has this complete topology
what we have defined. Means
Let's say this is my task.
Any
event come.
Okay? So, this is picked by a task and
it has a complete topology. Like source,
then you have a processors, then sink.
So, that will get processed.
Okay?
Each task has its complete topology.
Number of task equals to number of
partitions.
Each task run one partition. So,
take an example.
I have a topic, order-events,
which has two part partition, P0 and P1.
So,
as per the definition, we can have
maximum two tasks, task one, task two.
Okay? So, this task
you can say that for each partition, one
task is get created.
So, and each task has the full topology.
So, this is topology, source.
Okay? So, this source is like topic,
order-events, partition P0.
Then, the processors like different
step, step one, step two, step three.
And if they have to if this task has to
store something, it maintain its own
RocksDB.
Okay? And then, sync.
Similarly, we have task two. Its source
is order-events, partition P1.
The complete topology it it has it has
multiple processors, step one, step two,
step three. It if it need to store
certain information, it maintain its own
RocksDB.
And
ultimately sync it.
Clear? So, task is a unit of
parallelism. When we are saying
parallelism in
Kafka Streams means two tasks are
running in parallel.
Okay? But, events within a task
processed one by one.
Okay.
So, now, one thing is at this point of
time, who already works with Kafka
Streams,
at this point of time, when I said each
task has complete topology,
they might have got a doubt. Is it true?
Is it like complete topology is hold by
one task?
Actually, this is wrong.
Okay? I'll tell you why.
So, I have mentioned here each task has
complete topology. Actually, this is not
fully true. Why?
Let's go one level more deeper.
There is a concept of sub-topology. Very
confusing part.
Okay? And many times I see
engineering miss this topic itself
because it's not a bad easy to grasp.
So, I'll show you.
But this is where this line becomes
>> [snorts]
>> wrong. Like each task has complete
topology. Now, let's see that.
Sometimes we need repartition.
In that case, one big topology is
internally divided among multiple
sub-topologies.
So, to understand the topology, we have
to understand repartition. What does
repartition How repartition divide our
topology into multiple sub-topologies?
So, let's understand this.
So, I am taking one use case.
So, we have
order event. Okay? So, order event has
let's say key order ID and the value
your order object.
What we have to do is we need to find
out the product-wise order count. Let's
say product ID one, it has total 50
orders total.
Product ID two, it has total 100 orders.
This is our goal.
Okay? And from the event, you can find
out not directly because the key is
order ID. Let's say one customer is C1,
product ID is let's say P1.
So, for this P1
this order is for this product, right?
So, you can say that it will get counted
for this.
Okay? So, like this we have to
find. This is our goal.
So, So need to understand the problem if
there is no repartition first.
Like there is no concept of repartition
itself. Let's understand what's the
problem.
So events are distributed across topic
partitions. So for example, product P1
orders are distributed across two
partition of topic order events. What
does it mean? So now let's say in a
Kafka cluster
we have a topic order hyphen events
which has two partition, partition zero,
partition one.
So partition zero will have certain
events.
Okay?
Similarly, partition one also has
certain events.
So now let's say our goal is that
product
wise count. Product product ID, let's
say product one.
Let's say
we need to count orders.
So now here if you see
this event
product ID P1.
So this order belongs to product ID P1,
which is in present in partition P0.
Similarly, here if you see
there is one more event
which is again for product ID P1.
So this order is also for the same
product.
So partition zero
partition zero
has two orders
for
product one.
Similarly
partition one
has
product ID P1, so this order belongs to
the product ID P1. So partition one has
one order
for product ID one.
Okay? So currently this is our
situation. Because in uh
topic a particular topic
the events can be distributed among
partition. Correct? That's we already
know that.
Now in the Kafka stream I told you we
have different tasks. Let's say task
one, task two. So the number of
partition we have, that number of tasks
we will have. So we will have let's say
our topology is this.
Source, read from order event. So our
topology first
Our topology is
a read from
order-events.
This is our source.
After that
our processors.
Processor is like
group by let's say
group by
product ID.
Then you have to do count.
And ultimately we have to
put sink in output topic.
That's our topology. Now let's say our
each task hold this topology.
Okay? So this each task hold this
complete topology.
Now what would happen? You know that
each task handles one partition.
So our source is order event. So task
one
order event it handle partition zero.
Similarly task two
for order event handles partition one.
Okay? So they are both tasks are
handling different partition.
Now this task will see
when it do group by key product ID, it
will see that okay
because it will read the partition zero.
So when it will read partition zero, it
will see that hey for P1
there are two orders.
Similarly task two will see that hey for
P1 there is only one order.
Now which one is true?
How to aggregate?
That's the problem.
Okay? So you got the problem? Now, let's
understand repartition. What repartition
How repartition solves it.
So,
this is our topology.
Okay? So, now here if you see that
the source is order event, the processor
In the processor, let's say this is the
one processing step which does
repartition.
Okay? And after that, again same group
by key
count and ultimately sink.
Now, what would happen?
See this, how the task is created.
So, first it create topology,
sub-topology.
So, sub-topology zero.
You have a source, yes source.
Order hyphen events, so source is order
hyphen event.
Then the processor.
So, in the processor it has let's say
select key product ID, this one. Select
key product ID.
So, this is step is
of repartition step.
So, what we are trying to do is that in
order events
topic,
we have multiple partition, partition
zero, partition one.
So, we have
events here.
We have certain events here
for the same product ID.
Same product ID.
Now, what we are doing is
whenever we are getting an event,
we are saying that repartition based on
product ID. So, what it does is
when it get an event, particular event
now, which has let's say product ID P1.
What it will do is it will again put
into a
topic,
certain repartition topic,
which has again the same number of
partition, P0
P1. So, this has let's say two
partition, order event.
So, the same number of partition it
creates.
Okay? So, it's a new This partition is
created internally. We are not doing
anything. We just created this topology.
This is in our hand.
We don't know about like what internally
how it is internally creating sub
topology and all. It internally does
that. But, internal functionality I'm
showing you. Okay? But, this topology is
which we created. Here we haven't
defined any sub topology and all. We
just defined it steps.
We just told that, "Hey, repartition is
based on product ID."
And after that next step, next step,
like this.
But, internally what it does is
first it gives that, "Okay, source is
okay." Then processor, "Hey,
you want me to do repartition? Okay."
So, what it will do repartition is that
it will create a new topic.
Which has the same number of partitions
of the source one.
Okay? So, P0 P1. Now, in the
repartition, it will do based on this
product ID. So, now here
when our producer publish an order
event,
the key was order ID.
Not the product ID, order ID.
Okay? Now, here is during the
repartition our key is now product ID.
Okay? Value is the same order, whatever
here it was.
But, the key is changed. Now, it is
product ID. Now, since key is same,
all these events will goes to only one
partition, either P0 or either P1.
Okay?
So,
here if you see
in the processor, select key product ID.
So, this is a repartition step.
And when a repartition step, the its
sync
is the repartition topic.
Okay? So, it will ultimately create a
repartition topic. And whatever the
event is, it will just publish them
again, but now with a key product ID.
So, that all these events
now goes to one of the partition only,
not divide like earlier.
Okay? So, this is sub-topology zero.
Then, sub-topology one is like read from
source is now this partition topic.
Now, from this part
repartition topic,
it will read.
And then do the
following step, group by key,
count,
and the sync, whatever the sync where
you wanted to put.
So, you got it? Internally, it divides.
Okay? So,
whenever you want to do repartition, it
will first create or insert it into the
repartition topic,
like whatever the event come.
Okay? And based on the task which you
have performed, whenever do you want to
do repartition, it will just repartition
based on your key which you have
provided. So, it will go back again to
the certain topic.
And from there, you have to read it
again and complete the step.
Okay? So, the same example I have shown
here.
We just created topology based on the
processor. If repartition requirement
framework internally automatically
create repartition topic and create
sub-topologies. I told you in all
we just work with topology.
Sub-topology is an internal concept.
That's why
many times engineer miss it because we
don't create topology.
We We don't create sub topology. We just
only create topology.
Okay?
Based on the our processing or based on
a step, if that step is repartition
step, internally it creates sub
topology.
So, see this example. I hope with that
everything will get clear now. So, let's
say order event. It has two partition,
partition zero, partition one.
I told you that when the producer has
published into this,
the key was order ID.
Value was order.
Okay? So, your order has process ID and
all, but since key is order ID,
partition zero has certain data.
Partition one has certain data.
Okay?
Now, after repartition, so repartition
now key become
your product ID.
P1.
And then the same order.
The key is now this.
So, for the key is P1,
order is this.
01 C1 P1.
Similarly,
the key is P1. When this event is get,
it will just republish it.
-03
C3 this one. So, all these events
ultimately when the task
what it will do is it will do
repartition it. And
during repartition what would happen is
now because of the same key,
they will all goes to only one partition
of a repartition topic.
So, that when you further read it,
okay? You will have a task.
Okay? You will have a task here on this
also. Partition zero, partition one. So,
you have two tasks here.
Uh which looks at partition zero, task
which looks at partition one of this
repartition topic.
So, only one task now will get all these
events now. So, it will able to see
properly clear. Uh process ID, let's say
P-1, count is three.
Okay?
Earlier, it was
two and one here. Now, with the
repartition
this get resolved.
Got it?
Now, let's comes to task again.
Okay?
Earlier, I told you that
earlier, I told you that each task has
complete topology. Now, we have an
understanding of sub topology also. So,
I would just rephrase that
each task has complete sub topology for
a specific partition.
So,
just see this example
till here.
So, see this cluster and see this
topology.
Pause it here.
Divide this topology into sub topology
and after that see how many task it
required.
Okay?
So, now let's say our Kafka cluster has
only order events and
this order events has two partition, P0
and P1.
And this is my topology which I have
created that source is like order event.
And then this is the processor.
So, in the processor, the first it is
doing is
repartition
based on the product ID.
Group by the key. Third is count, so
multiple step.
After that, sink.
Sink to the topic product or order
count. So, this is our output topic, you
can say that.
Now, we know that
this
this step is the repartition step.
Re-
partition step. So, we know that it will
create multiple sub topologies. Can we
create different sub topology?
This is one sub sub topology. This is
second sub topology. Source is order
even.
Okay.
Processor select key by product ID.
Re-partition happen at this step.
So, it will sync into certain
re-partition topic.
Okay? So, now this will create a new
topic into our Kafka cluster
re-partition topic, which has the same
number of partition which your source
has. So, source has P0 P1, it will also
have P0 P1.
Okay?
Now, sub topology one. It will read from
this re-partition topic. It will read
from this re-partition topic.
Now, further step. Group by key, count.
Group by key count and the sync product
order count.
So, there will be some other topic. It
will sync it there.
Okay? So, how many task will be created?
So, this is also certain work we have to
do. This is also certain work we have to
do. So, for let's say for this sub
topology.
This sub topology
has two partitions. Source is two
partition. So, task
one.
Sub topology zero.
Partition zero.
Task two.
Sub topology zero.
Partition one.
Okay? So, sub topology zero source is
order events, right? So, it's
has order event has two partition. So,
sub topology zero
means this is this has to be
done in a particular task.
But, partition zero. So, whatever the
source is order even, it's partition
zero.
Similarly, like this. Okay, so
0 0 here, sub topology zero, partition
zero.
So
source is order events, partition P0.
And the whole topology, processor
select key
sync is repartition topic. So, this is
one now sub topology, right? This.
Okay? Now, second is task 0 1. Sub
topology is zero, partition is one.
So, order events, but partition is P1.
Okay?
The The rest of the sub topology,
complete sub topology, select key, and
it will publish into repartition topic.
Okay?
Now, let's comes to this sub
sub topology.
This source, repartition topic, also has
now two partitions. So, means it need
two tasks.
So, task 1 0. One is like sub topology
one, partition zero.
So, its source is
So, its source is repartition topic. So,
repartition topic, partition P0.
Repartition topic, partition P0.
And a processor, rest all same.
Okay?
This all same.
Similarly, task 1 1. Sub topology one,
partition one. So, topic was repartition
topic, it's partition P1, it will read.
Rest all same. Group by key, count,
ultimately sync.
So, you got it? So, the now task, number
of task is like
depend upon your sub topology.
So, for each sub topology
it will check its source.
So, this source topic, whatever the
partition it has, that many
task it will create.
Okay, so this topology has order events.
Order event has two
partition.
So,
task one, task two for this one.
Similarly, this sub-topology, its source
repartition topic has two partition. So,
for this also has task one, task two for
this one, this sub-topology.
So, task is created per sub-topology.
Okay?
It's clear now?
Now, this four task will be distributed
to our stream application instances. So,
whatever the Spring Boot application
which we will create for stream
processing, these four tasks will be
distributed among them. Let's say I'm
creating a Spring Boot application with
thread two.
Mean two threads I'm creating.
So, now this four task will get
distributed among this two threads. So,
thread one, thread two. So, this four
tasks
is distributed among
this two threads. This four tasks
distributed among this two threads.
Okay?
So, at this point of time, now you got
one doubt
regarding RocksDB.
So, you might be thinking first is like
what is RocksDB?
Okay, by the diagram we'll see that
if we reconnect the dots
from start,
each task, so here the last diagram you
see, each task, if you see each
task, the smallest unit,
each task maintain its own RocksDB.
Okay? Each task maintain its own
RocksDB. So, we have four task, four
tasks maintain its own RocksDB.
Okay?
So,
and you know that RocksDB is nothing but
a
key-value
file
is stored in
local disk.
So, RocksDB is nothing
but a key-value stored in a file in your
disk.
So, now the question might have come
that, "Okay,
so this task is maintain its own RockDB
file. This task is maintain its own
RockDB file. And this two task is
running in this instance, instance one.
Similarly,
task three, task four is maintain their
own RockDB files and they are running
into this thread and this two threads
are running into this application. What
if this application get died?
So, all this RockDB file
will get
because it's on a local disk, right? So,
this data go get lost.
Because see, once your machine get die,
this task will be assigned to some other
machine.
Okay, rebalance will happen.
So, okay, earlier your machine one where
your instance was running, so they have
us like task one, task two, task three,
task four.
Now, this machine dies,
so a new machine would be assigned this
task one, task two, task three, task
four.
But,
the question is that each task maintains
the
RocksDB local file.
This maintain its own RocksDB. This
maintain its own But, and it's there in
the machine one.
If the machine one is died,
how they
task is moved to another machine, but
what about the data which is which was
present into the local disk?
How it will get moved?
So, the answer for this is that
the change log topic. There is one more
topic. like whenever we insert
data into the RocksDB.
Okay, it will also publish an events to
this change log topic.
So that even when the machine goes down
and the task moves to another machine,
they will fetch
there is a change log
topic.
From there it will fetch
and rebuild the
RocksDB.
Okay? So, now see this complete diagram.
Things will get clear now. Okay?
So, earlier Kafka cluster is you have
let's say order events partition zero,
partition one.
Correct?
So now based on your topology, let's say
multiple sub topologies created for
topologies created, right?
So, let's say
four tasks created. Tasks
So you have just to recap, you have
topology you have created. Two sub
topology was created. Sub topology zero,
sub topology one.
Okay?
So it put into repartition topic. It
will read from repartition topic and
ultimately put into the sink.
Okay?
So
now we have four tasks. So the same
thing like we have four task one, task
two, task three, task four. The same
thing here I have written just
So task zero zero means sub topology
zero, partition zero.
So sub topology zero. So sub topology
zero was like read from order hyphen
events.
But it's a task, right? Partition P0.
Similarly, sub topology zero, partition
one.
Source is read from order hyphen events.
But partition P1. So that's different
task.
And the rest of those sub-topology
processor select key
sync.
Okay? Like similarly, we have
sub-topology one partition
zero. So, sub-topology one says that
read from repartition topic.
But since this task switch partition P0.
Similarly, another partition P1.
So,
here, if you see,
it will sync
your sub-topology
your task 00. Now, can you read this?
When I say task 00, what does it mean?
Task 00 means sub-topology task which is
associated with sub-topology zero
partition zero.
So, sub-topology zero, you know that it
read from order-events
partition P0 now.
Okay? And ultimately, it sync into
repartition topic. Now, repartition
topic here, if you see,
has two same P0 P1. So, in which one it
will
store it? It depend.
Okay? Because you will publish on based
on the product ID.
The key is your product ID. So, whether
it will go into P0 or P1 depends.
Correct?
Now, see this one.
I told you that it also has a change
log.
So, now let's say
this
step
this task is also has certain
just assume that certain a step
which
touch the RocksDB, which it stores into
RocksDB.
Okay? Similarly, the sub-topology one
also has certain a step
which touch the RocksDB.
So, now you know that
there will be change log present for
this.
There would be a change log present for
this also.
Okay?
So now let's say for the sub topology
zero,
I have given the RockDB name is let's
say order-store.
So a change log order-store-changelog
will get created.
Okay?
And it has the same number of partition
like your source has.
So your source order-event has two
partition, right? P0 P1. So
this order-store-changelog
will also have two, P0 P1.
Okay. So this task 00 means sub topology
zero, partition zero.
So it will sync where?
It will sync into P0.
The change log it will put into P0.
Because it is processing the P0 events.
Okay?
Similarly, this sub topology zero
partition one,
the RockDB is let's say order-store, so
its change log would be
order-store-changelog.
And in which change log partition it
will publish an event whenever any
certain event uh is certain data is
updated into RockDB, it will publish an
event to the
order-store-changelog,
but partition P1.
Here. So this will touch partition P1
change log.
Now sub topology one. Now sub topology
one let's say the RockDB is count-store.
Okay? Similarly, it has partition P0
partition P1. So this RockDB whenever
any change happen, it will publish an
event to count-store-changelog.
And it will touch its partition P0.
Similarly, this sub topology will have
RockDB count-store-changelog,
but which partition it will touch? P1.
Okay?
So, all I just wanted to show that, like
even though
the RocksDB
is local, stored on a local, but it will
also publish an event, which ultimately
stored into the Kafka cluster, and there
is a change log
topic itself.
In that, it will get it stored.
This is clear?
Don't worry about this if you have any
confusion.
At this point of time,
agenda is that we know the high level.
We know
like what is repartition, topology,
sub-topology,
RocksDB, okay?
And uh
all this, like I say, complete
end-to-end picture should be in mind.
So, now we know the architecture of
Kafka stream. Let's see the complete
flow, like a Kafka consumer. So, now you
will see that, okay, the same flow which
we have seen in Kafka consumer,
mostly the same.
So, step one. Now, let's say our stream
application got started. I have given a
group ID stream analytics.
Okay? So, what it will do?
It will find out the consumer offset,
like the partition number of the topic
consumer offset. So, you know that there
are 50
partitions of consumer offsets.
Okay? So, it need to find out that,
okay, whatever the group ID I have
given,
who like which partition is my group
coordinator?
Like, so first it will find out that,
okay, hash of
your group ID mod 50, so 23.
So, partition, so it need to find out
that, okay, the partition 23 will hold
all the information related to my group.
And it just need to find out that
who is the group coordinator for this
partition 23. Exactly same as the Kafka
consumer part.
So, it will send a request to any
broker. Broker will goes to the
controller. Controller will take out the
metadata. Metadata with return will have
that, okay, consumer offset partition
zero leader is broker one. Partition two
leader is broker three.
Similarly, like three partition 23
broker is uh leader is broker three.
So, it gets certain information.
So, after that it will send
the request to the broker three that,
"Hey, I want to join the stream
analytics group." Everything same.
Now, here very
something different happen than the
consumer.
Now, the group coordinator
wait for all the members to join.
Okay? So, group coordinator will wait
for all the members to join.
Let's say there are let's say 10
instance, 20 instance, whatever the
instances.
Now, what it will do is that
they will run the streams partitioner.
If you remember in the consumer, what
happened was let's say you have multiple
instance of consumer, consumer one,
consumer two, consumer three.
They all wanted to join let's say
order-events.
And order-events has let's say two
three partition, partition zero,
partition one, partition two.
So, this partition will be assigned to
one of the consumers.
But, now in case of stream, I told you
that the task is the
working unit.
Okay? So, what it does is it runs this
stream partitioner.
So, this
discover topology, create sub topology,
create task.
Okay? It
internally create repartition topic,
change log topic, whatever the things
required.
Okay? And then distribute the task to
the stream instances.
Okay? So, now let's say it says that
whatever the application you are saying
that, "Hey, you have to handle task 0
\comma} 2."
Means sub-topology 0
partition 2.
Okay?
Got it? This is one difference. So, it
does lot of things that discover
topology, sub-topology, task creation,
and create change log, repartition,
everything.
Now, you got the
task which you need to run.
Okay? So, now
it will check.
Okay, I need
Okay, so sub-topology
partition
2. So, it knows that sub from
sub-topology 0, it knows that the
sub-topology 0, its source is
order-events.
Okay? So, now it will say that, "Okay,
for order-events, partition 2,
till what offsets
it is read properly?" So, it will just
ask that, "Hey,
fetch the last offset for the
order-events partition 2." Like
similarly like a consumer.
Okay? So, it will say that, "Okay, till
100, it's all read. You have to proceed
further."
Same. Now, one thing another new is that
you every task maintains a RocksDB. So,
now since it's a new application, it
need to restore that RocksDB. So, it
will read its
So, for this order-events, so this
sub-topology. So, sub-topology 0
partition 2
it will read or recover the change
RocksDB from the change log.
Okay?
So, let's you can say that sub topology
let's say zero
partition P1.
So, it will know that
the RocksDB the name is order-store
because in the topology we have given
the name. When we have defined the
topology, we have given the name
order-store
So, order-store-change-log,
which partition? P1 it has to read.
order-store-change-log
from partition P1, it will recover.
Okay?
So, it has partition two, so it will
read partition two let's say. It will
recover the
RocksDB.
Okay?
Now, what it will do is
it will invoke the leader
and fetch the data.
Because it is now has to fetch like
order-events partition two data, right?
So, it will invoke the broker, read the
data one by one.
Okay? So, now let's say it got the data.
Now,
it will
process it. So, task has all the sub
topology, right? So, it will process it.
So, like this one.
Now, all the tasks which has to do it
will do.
After that, it will commit the same like
a consumer and
continues to the step nine. So, the
again
fetch the next event
process the task
commit it continue again.
Exactly same as consumer. If you have
understood the consumer architecture,
this is the same flow. Only difference
is that
the group coordinator, how the earlier
partition was divided
uh among the consumer instances, now
task is divided among the
stream instances.
Okay? And it also has one more step
where it will recover the RocksDB state
from the changelog.
After that, everything is same like
it once it get the event
the logic which has to be processed is
within present in the task itself. So,
every task has this sub-topology.
It has to process that.
These are steps.
Clear? So, I would say that go through
it once again.
Because things get little complex in
this one like understanding
sub-topology,
uh understanding this changelog.
So, go through it one more time.
And try to connect dots.
Okay? Just see that like all we do is
that we create topology.
Okay? From the topology, internally
happens everything. It creates
sub-topology internally.
Okay? It divide this topology into
multiple sub-topologies internally.
Got it?
So, any doubt
let me know.
Because in the next step, I will just
set do a setup of this stream.
And once we are done with the setup,
then we will do like go depth into the
processors.
Like what are different processors we
have? Filter, group, count, and etc.
Okay? But, I hope this stream
architecture is clear because that is
critical.
Okay, guys. Thank you. Bye.